Judson Memorial Church Oral History Archive 2008 MSS 232
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series III: Oral History Interview Audio Discs, 2008
  - Subseries A: Audio - Access Copies, 2008
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part One, Disc Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 10/15/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0095)
      Track 3: Dance, Poets Theatre
      Track 4: Publicity and growth
      Track 5: Clashes with the NYC and NYU
      Track 6: Runaway shelter, mobile clinic
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc One, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0097)
      Howard Moody Oral History (Part 2)
      Disc 1 of 3 (176:47 minutes total)
      Track 1: Late 1960s, runaway projects
      Track 2: Runaway youth arts program
      Track 3: Politics and social change (1968)
      Track 4: Abortion Clinic
      Track 5: Clergy Consultation Service
      Track 6: Prostitution Project
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0099)
      Disc 2 of 3 (176:47 minutes total)
      Track 7: Prostitution Project/AIDS Task force
      Track 8: 1990, financial crisis
      Track 9: Welcoming Church, growth of Judson
      Track 10: Looking back from now, treatise
      Track 11: Civil Rights movement, involvement
      Track 12: Current (2008) gay issues, Prop 8
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc Three, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0101)
      Disc 3 of 3 (176:47 minutes total)
      Track 13: 1968 Democratic Convention experience
      Track 14: Vietnam War -- protest movement
      Track 15: Physical Space of Judson
      Track 16: American exceptionalism
      Track 17: Worship service at Judson, changes
      Track 18: Censorship
      Track 19: Let things go...
      Track 20: Representative of Congregation
    - Maxine Phillips Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 10/21/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0103)
      Judson Church Oral History Project: Maxine Phillips
      October 21, 2008
      Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi
      Disc 1 of 2 (1:53:47)
      Judson Church Oral History Project
      Track 1: Childhood in Pennsylvania
      Track 2: Parent's Background and History
      Track 3: Religious Background
      Track 4: Sense of Being the 'Other'
      Track 5: Academic Background
      Track 6: Study Abroad in France
      Track 7: Graduate School at Syracuse
      Track 8: Religious Involvement in College
      Track 9: Children's Religious Upbringing
      Track 10: Introduction to Judson Church
      Track 11: Runaway House at Judson
      Track 12: Organizing Welfare Rights at Judson
      Track 13: Communal Living in Brooklyn
      Track 14: Child Welfare League
      Track 15: Life Planning Project at Judson
      Track 16: Courtship and Wedding to Tom Roderick
      Track 17: 1980s - Motherhood and Career at Dissent
      Track 18: Reflections on Judson Church - Why Judson?
    - Maxine Phillips Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 10/21/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0105)
      Disc 2 of 2 (1:53:47)
    - Anna Lou Pickett Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/19/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0107)
    - Anna Lou Pickett Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/19/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0109)
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0111)
      Tom Roderick
      Part 1 of 3
      Interviewed by Adina Langer
      10/24/08
      wav file
      37:53
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0113)
      Tom Roderick Part 2 of 3 Interviewed by Adina Langer 10/24/08 wav file 42:09 Judson Church Oral History Project
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part Three, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0115)
      Tom Roderick Part 3 of 3 Interviewed by Adina Langer 10/24/08 wav file 42:14 Judson Church Oral History Project
    - Tamara Rowe Oral History, Interviewed by Keara Duggan, 11/02/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0117)
      Tamara Oral History
      November 2, 2008
      Interviewed by Keara Duggan
      Disc 1 of 1 (56 min 50 sec)
      For NYU Oral History Course - Fall 2008
      Track 1: Introduction by Keara Duggan
      Track 2: Brooklyn Neighborhoods
      Track 3: Joining the Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church
      Track 4: Childhood in Bedford Stuyvesant and Food
      Track 5: Living in Fort Greene
      Track 6: Career as a Teacher
      Track 7: Teaching and Higher Education
    - Carolee Schneemann Oral History, Interviewed by Joanna Steinberg, 11/25/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0119)
      Carolee Schneeman Oral History
      11/25/2008
      Disc 1 (45 minutes)
      Track 1: Introduction to Judson Church; early uses of the body in art; "protofeminist" and "transgressive" movement in Judson Dance Theater; coherence and dissention in choreographic styles within the Judson group; emergence of art scene at Judson Church in 1960s
      Track 2: Continued emergence of art scene at Judson; meaning of church as a space for performance; relationship between artists and members of Judson Church; Schneemann's artistic process
      Track 3: Audience members and their responses; Newspaper Event; Meet Joy; Freedom of Expression at Judson Church; political implications of Judson aesthetic; relevant political issues and involvement (anti-Vietnam movement and feminism)
      Track 4: "Interior Scroll"; inclusion of women in art criticism; teaching positions and practices; overall impressions and reflections on experiences at Judson Church
    - Rachel Tenney and Bethene Trexel Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 11/19/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0121)
      Judson Oral History Project:
      Rachel Tenney and Bethnene Trexel
      November 19, 2008
      Disc 1 of 2 (1:27:5)
      Track 1: Childhood at Judson
      Track 2: Teenage Years at Judson
      Track 3: Youth Activities/Teaching Judson Beliefs
      Track 4: Past and Present Activism at Judson
      Track 5: Acceptance and Activism
      Track 6: Teaching Sunday School at Judson
      Track 7: Leaving Judson, Macalester College
      Track 8: Personal Growth/Changes at Judson
      Track 9: Bethnene's Description of Rachel's Childhood at Judson
      Track 10: Growth of Congregation
      Track 11: Rachel's Baptism at Judson
      Track 12: Bethnene's Reaction to Rachel's Rededication
      Track 13: Bethnene's Childhood/Religious Background
      Track 14: Bethnene's experience in NYC/Judson Church
      Track 15: Bethnene's Activism work during Rachel's Childhood
    - Rachel Tenney and Bethene Trexel Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 11/19/2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 232.0123)
      Disc 2 of 2 (1:27:5)
  - Subseries B: Audio - Originals, 2008
    - Bebe Anderson Oral History, Interviewed by Ashley Welch, 12/9/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.001)
    - Holly Bean Oral History, Interviewed by Elizabeth Banks, 11/18/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0002)
    - Reathel Bean Oral History, Interviewed by Kait Medley, 10/10/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0003)
    - Keen Berger Oral History, Interviewed by Elizabeth Banks, 10/10/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0004)
    - Malcolm Goldstein Oral History, Interviewed by Joanna Steinberg, 10/16/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0005)
    - Grace Goodman Oral History, Interviewed by Brigid Harmon, 10/16/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0006)
    - Peggy Halsey Oral History, Interviewed by Ashley Welch, 10/20/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0007)
    - Sue Harwig Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/17/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0008)
    - Sue Harwig Oral History Part Two, Interviewed Adina Langer, 10/17/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0009)
    - Sue Harwig Oral History Part Three, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/17/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0010)
    - Rose James Oral History Part One, 10/17/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0011)
    - Rose James Oral History Part Two, 11/10/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0012)
    - Harry Koutoukas Oral History, Interviewed by Kait Medley, 11/11/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0013)
    - Arthur Levin Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/24/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0014)
    - Arthur Levin Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/24/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0015)
    - Mary Meyer Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/26/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0016)
    - Mary Meyer Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/26/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0017)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part One, Disc One, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 10/15/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0018)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part One, Disc Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 10/15/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0019)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc One, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0020)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0021)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc Three, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0022)
    - Maxine Phillips Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 10/21/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0023)
    - Maxine Phillips Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 10/21/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0024)
    - Anna Lou Pickett Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/19/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0025)
    - Anna Lou Pickett Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/19/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0026)
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0027)
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0028)
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part Three, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0029)
    - Tamara Rowe Oral History, Interviewed by Keara Duggan, 11/02/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0030)
    - Carolee Schneemann Oral History, Interviewed by Joanna Steinberg, 11/25/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0031)
    - Steve Studnicka Oral History, Interviewed by Brigid Harmon, 12/02/2008 [No Readable Access Copy Available] (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0032)
    - Rachel Tenney and Bethene Trexel Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 11/19/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0033)
    - Rachel Tenney and Bethene Trexel Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 11/19/2008 (Box 3, Media ID: 232.0034)
  - Audio CD Inserts, 2008; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)